What is it like just sitting here in the
Steelers facility, a place that you did
not grow up that far from?
>> Yeah. Um I feel like um it's crazy, you
know, to be here. It's amazing just to,
you know, be, you know, in the presence
of, you know, legends of, if you think
about it, like the just the blueprint of
everything, you know, the steel city,
you know, what it means, you know,
everything behind it. Um, I feel like
it's a it's a surreal moment. Like I
walked in here, I I got the chill,
especially looking at the trophies. I
mean, I seen too, but you know, just
seeing the history, you know, of
everything and, you know, the fans and
what it means to the city, you know, the
the city of champions and things like
that, I feel like it's it's amazing. So,
>> what did football mean to you growing up
specifically in high school and as you
furthered your career?
>> Yeah, I feel like I started playing
football around what, four or five years
old and in Pittsburgh, you know,
football's, you know, huge. You know,
you look at, you know, the roots of it,
you know, all the legends I passed
through here. You look at the Hall of
Famers, they really came from
Pennsylvania and Pittsburgh. So, um,
just being, you know, growing up there,
just knowing, you know, how important
football is and going to a powerhouse
like Gateway, like you said, um, you
know, just being around, you know, a lot
of great athletes, you know, a lot of
legends as pest doer and, you know,
things like that. So, I feel like I
mean, football, it meant a lot to me.
>> Awesome. I want to show you something
and you can just press play.
Oh my gosh. Let's see what this kid is
talking about.
>> Jaquan Brisker. I play safety and
receiver and I go to Gateway High
School.
>> We'll kick the ball and it's going to go
high in the air and
2530 35 40 35 30 25 20 five touchdown. I
describe my player as physical,
athletic, and I can make plays when when
my team needs me to make plays. I wear
number three because my brother pass and
he play I gay also and he had number
three. So, I'm wearing number three for
my brother.
>> That's crazy. I need the ball back in my
ass.
>> My favorite music artist is Meek Mill.
He's like a serious rapper and you know
that he's the best.
>> My favorite athlete would be Earl Thomas
because he has a passion for a game. He
takes the game serious and he flies
around the ball. My favorite homemade
meal would be my mom.
>> My mom makes it. It's her recipe like
and I like it.
>> Yeah, that's so true. That's so true.
>> My name is Jaquan Brisker and that's my
blue chip spotlight.
We'll have to get you a copy.
>> I definitely do need that. That's
hilarious.
>> What do you think that kid in that video
would be saying right now if he was
sitting in this chair?
>> Man, you know, being a a kid from the
city of Pittsburgh. Um, and being in
this position, you know, we're just
blessed. We're just humbled. Um, you
know, where we came from. um you know
the the work we had to put in to get
here and know to be in the hometown
playing you know for the city you know
in front of the fans you know for my
family people like for the last name
back in my jersey know it's it's crazy I
feel like you know that kid you know he
knew he had a future but he just didn't
know how you know it would you know how
it would continue so that's crazy
>> you answered a lot of questions in there
foods different things are all those
still true
>> yeah maybe not the favorite rapper part,
but everything else is pretty much
>> That's okay. That was high school.
>> That was high school. Yeah.
>> In terms of telling people that you were
going to sign with the Steelers, who did
you call first and what family members
and friends got to know?
>> My mom. My mom was the first one I
called. I'm like, "Mom, I'm stealer."
She like, "You sure, baby?" I'm like,
"Yeah, I'm a stealer." She like, "Oh my
gosh, I'm so excited." And then I had to
tell my mom, had to tell my father, um
had to tell, you know, my friends, um my
brothers, you know, sisters, things like
that. Really, my whole family. Um and
everybody was just so excited. I was
like, "This is meant to be." And I and I
thought the same thing. I said, "It is
meant to be, you know." Um I felt the
love, you know, immediately and
obviously um you know, grew up here and
things like that. So, you know, I feel
like it's going to be an amazing journey
for sure.
>> In terms of Joey Porter Jr., Did you
tell him or did he somehow find out
before?
>> To be honest, he he was already ringing
like, "What are you going to do? What
are you going to do?"
>> He was recruiting.
>> Yeah, he was recruiting. So, I'm like,
"I'm probably going to be a Steeler."
And he, you know, kept calling. Then he
called my agent. He's like, "What's
going on?" So, when he called my agent,
I'm like, "Oh, yeah. It's serious." So,
like like I said, me and Joey talk all
the time. So, um I'm Well, I called him
on FaceTime. I'm like, "I'm about to be
a Steeler for real." I'm like, "Let's
go." I start sc like ah he's like let's
go you know we were so excited. It was
it was a great moment. So
>> how cool would that be that you played
in college together and now you're doing
it at the next level.
>> It's I mean it's amazing cuz in college
um you know we were young but we were
still you know great teammates but you
know we performed on the field and then
now you know we try to train with each
other every year. So um just moving
forward um being able to play with each
other is is going to be amazing. like he
obviously got older, he's more mature.
Um we got a lot more swagger, things
like that. Um and you know, we make
plays and that's what the city needs.
So, it's going to be amazing getting
back with Joey and you know, I miss
playing with him and I always told him
we need to link up and now it's now it's
here. So, it's going to be amazing.
>> It's perfect. Last one for you. Uh what
are you bringing to this team, to this
defense?
>> Yeah. Um I'll say leadership. um some
swagger, passion, you know, um you know,
care for the game and a lot of
playmaking ability. Um just, you know,
being around the football and helping my
teammates elevate, you know, get better.
Um you know, a lot of, you know, trash
talking too, but that's okay.
>> You know, things like that. Um just a
lot of a lot of different things. And I
feel like, you know, my teammates will
love me for it. And, you know, once
they, you know, feel my presence and,
you know, once they start making plays,
too, they going to see how happy I get
for them. So once they just see what
type of team I am, I feel like
everybody's going to be happy.
>> Well, welcome home. I don't get to say
that often.
>> Appreciate that. Thank you.